A Guide to the Agnes Repplier Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8351
Agnes Repplier Collection 1891-1925
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8351
30 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 1963 Dec 17 ] 1966 Aug 30
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Comedy of the Custom House, [1892]; AMsS, 25 p.
  - Words, [1893]; AMsS, 45 p.
  - Cakes and Ale, [1897]; AMsS, 48 p.
  - The Point of View, [1901]; AMsS, 41 p.
    [ALS 1901 Jan 30, attached to front, Agnes Repplier to [Horace Howard] Furness; states that the essay has been sold to
    Harper's [Weekly]
    and is their property although it has not yet been published.]
  - Christmas Shopping at Assuan, n. d.; AMsS, 33 p.
  - Fragment, p. 54, beginning "tethered to our kind.. .", AMsS, 1 p.
  - Fragment, p. 58, beginning "speeding swiftly on our path.. .", n. d.; AMsS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Agnes Repplier to the Editors of the Independent, 1891 Sep 18; ALS, 2 p.
    [Responds to request for short articles; writes that she is interested in writing on the trials of publisher John Murray, based on her reading of his memoir
    A Publisher and His Friends
    . ]
  - Agnes Repplier to H. O. Houghton & Co., 1893 Aug 7; ALS, 1 p.
    [Accompanies proofs of "
    Essays in Idleness
    . "]
  - Agnes Repplier to Morton G. Thalhimer, 1906 Feb 21; ALS, 2 p. w/env
    [Writes that she is willing to see him if he should call.]
  - Agnes Repplier to Mrs. J. W. Brannon, [1909] Apr 23; ALS, 3 p. w/env
    [Thanks her for agreeing to come; invites her for lunch with Alice Warren and Cornelia Frothingham; writes that this would give her the opportunity to convert to suffragette cause.]
  - Agnes Repplier to Mrs. J. W. Brannon, [1909] Apr 26; ALS, 2 p. w/env
    [Expresses sorrow on hearing of her illness, but urges her to join them for a "restful meal."]
  - Agnes Repplier to Mrs. Wheeler, 1913 Nov 30; ALS, 2 p.
    [Declines to participate in public meeting opposing "Women Suffrage"; writes that she is opposed to lawlessness but not to suffrage, which she thinks will not do much harm or good.]
  - Agnes Repplier to [Alice] Brown, 1914 Dec 9; ALS, 2 p.
    [Declines invitation to be guest of Boston Author's Club due to another commitment in Buffalo. ]
  - Agnes Repplier to [James Montgomery] Beck, 1917 Apr 18; ALS, 4 p.
    [Thanks him for [Harry Ernest] Brittain's "
    To Verdun from the Somme
    "; admires his introduction as well as the narrative itself; describes letter from Hicks critical of Beck and her negative reaction to it.]
  - Agnes Repplier to [James Montgomery] Beck, 1918 Feb 27; ALS, 2 p.
    [Congratulates him on election to membership in the Societe des Gens de Lettres, of which she had read in the
    [New York] Times
  - Agnes Repplier to Riverside Press, [1919] Apr 8; ALS, 2 p.
    [Explains provenance of geographical data in a piece on Dr. White, left uncorrected by White family; suggests emendation.]
  - Agnes Repplier to [Thomas Lansing] Masson, 1919 Aug 25; ALS, 2 p.
    [Responds to invitation to contribute to
    Life's
    "Dull Number"; hopes that her examples will be understood; mentions [William Jennings] Bryan, Ford, a society for American birth control, and a handbook for communicating with the dead.]
  - Agnes Repplier to [Bryon J.] Rees, 1919 Nov 16; ALS, 3 p.
    [Regrets that other commitments prevent her contributing new piece for Rees'
    Modern American Prose Selections
    believes that if previously published work were desired, permission could be obtained.]
  - [ James Montgomery Beck] to Agnes Repplier, 1920 Apr 5; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Accompanies piece from March number of
    The North American Review
    writes that, with her collaboration, they could have "made a classic."]
  - Agnes Repplier to [James Montgomery] Beck, 1920 Nov 15; ALS, 3 p.
    [Thanks him for sending
    The Passing of the New Freedom
    expresses admiration for the work; writes she is surprised by election results and expected women to vote heavily for the League [of Nations]. ]
  - [ James Montgomery Beck] to Agnes Repplier, 1920 Nov 18; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Appreciates her praise of his book; admires her work as an essayist; shares her surprise at recent election results.]
  - Agnes Repplier to Mr. Johnson, 1922 Jul 2; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thanks him for "
    Knights of the Rainbow
    " and praises his hopefulness.]
  - Agnes Repplier to Mrs. Smith, 1922 Oct 5; ALS, 4 p.
    [Thanks her for writing from Paris; regrets she cannot visit because of her work; hopes to see her and Margaret [Ferrand Thorp ?] following her speaking engagement in Summit, New Jersey. ]
  - [ James Montgomery Beck] to Agnes Repplier, 1923 Apr 24; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Discusses editorial in the
    [Philadelphia] Inquirer
    on Agnes Repplier's Pittsburgh speech; asks for a copy of the address; asks if she has received a copy of his book [
    The Constitution of the United States
    ].]
  - [ James Montgomery Beck] to Agnes Repplier, 1923 May 9; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Discusses clipping from the
    and his Gray's Inn lectures on the Constitution; mentions rise of the Labour Party in England and the honor he recently received from the English Bar.]
  - Agnes Repplier to [James Montgomery] Beck, 1923 May 20; ALS, 4 p.
    [Praises his Gray's Inn lectures, especially "The Great Convention" and "The Revolt Against Authority"; writes that she is concerned about the English Labour Party; mentions Sir Andrew MacPhail's comments on Americans' loyalty to their Constitution.]
  - [ James Montgomery Beck] to Agnes Repplier, 1923 May 22; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Expresses gratitude for her praise; states he received similar letter from [Francesco Saverio] Nitti, the Italian statesman; writes that, if third edition of his work is printed, he intends to add 2 lectures on the United States Supreme Court. ]
  - Agnes Repplier to James D[uff] Law, 1925 Apr 24; ALS, 2 p. w/env
    [Thanks him for letter and "the gallant Pennsylvania song"; states her willingness to see him if he should call.]
  - Agnes Repplier to [Thomas Lansing] Masson, n.y. Mar 13; ALS, 2 p.
    [Writes that she has "emerged" from hospital and both she and her work are less than sprightly; states he may print the pieces she submits or throw them away.]